<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<METS_Profile 
	xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
	xmlns:mets="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
	xmlns:rts="http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights/"
	xsi:schemaLocation="	http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/
				http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profile_docs/mets.profile.v1-2.xsd
				http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/
				http://dublincore.org/schemas/xmls/qdc/2006/01/06/dc.xsd
				http://purl.org/dc/terms/
				http://dublincore.org/schemas/xmls/qdc/2006/01/06/dcterms.xsd
				http://www.loc.gov/METS/     
				http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd
				http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights/
				http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights.xsd">
	<URI LOCTYPE="URL">http://www.loc.gov/mets/profiles/00000010.xml</URI>
	<title>CDL 7train Profile - CONTENTdm Simple and Complex Objects</title>
	<abstract>The California Digital Library (CDL) - http://www.cdlib.org - has created and uses this profile to 
		ingest and manage METS objects produced via the CONTENTdm software application (see http://contentdm.com/).  
		CDL has designed a transformation process to produce METS instances from CONTENTdm's Standard XML 
		export.  This profile was designed to accommodate objects produced as part of the Local History Digital 
		Resources Project, a project supported by the U.S. Institute of Museum and Library Services under the 
		provisions of the Library Service and Technology Act (LSTA), administered by the California State Librarian.  
		This profile may be used by other organizations that also use CONTENTdm and wish to submit objects to 
		the CDL.  The objects described by this profile are primarily imaged objects, including imaged text
		objects.  In the case of imaged text objects, the objects may also contain associated text transcriptions, 
		formatted as raw ASCII text. The principle goal of this documentation is to describe the salient features of 
		the profile and how it is used for the management of objects in CDL's systems.</abstract>
	<date>2006-05-01T13:46:00</date>
	<contact>
		<name>Paul Fogel</name>
		<address>415 20th Street - 4th Floor, Oakland, CA,  94612</address>
		<phone>510.987.0680</phone>
		<email>paul.fogel@ucop.edu</email>
	</contact>
	<related_profile>No related profiles</related_profile>
	<extension_schema>
		<name>Qualified Dublin Core: Elements</name>
	 	<URI>http://dublincore.org/schemas/xmls/qdc/2003/04/02/dc.xsd</URI>
    		<context>Used as the primary schema for descriptive metadata in the METS:dmdSec element.</context>
	</extension_schema>
	<extension_schema>
		<name>Qualified Dublin Core: Terms</name>
		<URI>http://dublincore.org/schemas/xmls/qdc/2003/04/02/dcterms.xsd</URI>
		<context>Used for some elements of descriptive metadata in the METS:dmdSec element.</context>
	</extension_schema>
	<description_rules>
		<p>All applications of the Dublin Core schema in conforming METS documents follow the Guidelines for 
			Implementing Dublin Core in XML published by the Dublin Core Metadata Initiative.</p>
	</description_rules>
	<controlled_vocabularies>
		<vocabulary>
			<name>7train Profile &lt;fileGrp&gt; and &lt;file&gt; USE attribute values</name>
			<values>
				<value>archive image</value>
				<value>reference image</value>
				<value>thumbnail image</value>
				<value>transcription</value>
			</values>
			<context ID="vc1" RELATEDMAT="fileSec4">
				<p>mets/fileSec/fileGrp/@USE</p>
				<p>mets/fileSec/fileGrp/file/@USE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>These are the supported values for &lt;file&gt; and
					&lt;fileGrp&gt; USE attributes in METS documents conforming to this
					profile.</p>
				<p>&quot;archive image&quot;, &quot;reference image&quot; and
					&quot;thumbnail image&quot; are appropriate values to describe the USE
					of image content files. &quot;archive image&quot; designates image
					masters; &quot;thumbnail image&quot; reduced size images or thumbnails;
					and &quot;reference image&quot; any intermediate resolutions intended for
					reference or display purposes.</p>
				<p>&quot;transcription&quot; is an appropriate value to describe text files 
					transcribed from imaged documents.  This content must be formatted as 
					raw, unstructured ASCII text.</p>
				<p>A given segment of the source material could be represented by more than one
					content file of a particular USE; for example, multiple reference images of 
					different resolutions.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
		<vocabulary>
			<name>7train Profile &lt;mets&gt; TYPE attribute values</name>
			<values>
				<value>image</value>
				<value>facsimile text</value>
			</values>
			<context ID="vc2" RELATEDMAT="metsRoot3">
				<p>mets@TYPE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>These are the supported values for the mets root element TYPE attribute in METS 
					documents conforming to this profile.</p>
				<p>&quot;image&quot; and &quot;facsimile text&quot; are appropriate values to 
					denote the type of object the METS describes.  &quot;image&quot; designates 
					an object that is composed of graphical materials; &quot;facsimile text&quot; 
					designates an object that is a text represented by graphical materials 
					(e.g. scanned documents).</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
	</controlled_vocabularies>
	<structural_requirements>
		<metsRootElement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot1">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt; element must include an OBJID attribute value
					that contains a valid ARK and that uniquely identifies the object.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot2">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt;element must include a LABEL attribute value.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot3" RELATEDMAT="vc2">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt;element must include a TYPE attribute value.  This value must
					conform to the list given in the controlled vocabularies section above.</p>
			</requirement>
		</metsRootElement>
		<metsHdr>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr1">
				<p>METS documents of this profile must contain a metsHdr element.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr2">
				<p>The &lt;metsHdr&gt; element must include a CREATEDATE attribute value.
					It should, but is not required to, include a LASTMODDATE attribute value 
					when this differs from the CREATEDATE value.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr3">
				<p>The &lt;metsHdr&gt; element must include a child &lt;agent&gt;
					element identifying the person or institution responsible for creating the METS
					object.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr4">
				<p>The &lt;metsHdr&gt; element must include a child &lt;altRecordID&gt; element 
					that contains the identifier used by the institution submitting this	object to CDL, but
					only when that value is not a valid ARK.  If an institution uses the ARK identifier scheme
					for their identifiers, the altRecordID may be omitted.</p>
			</requirement>
		</metsHdr>
		<dmdSec>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec1">
				<p>METS documents must contain a one or more &lt;dmdSec&gt; elements. Each 
					&lt;dmdSec&gt; may in turn contain a &lt;mdRef&gt; or a &lt;mdWrap&gt;.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec2">
				<p>The primary descriptive metadata section - which will appear sequentially as the 
					first &lt;dmdSec&gt; - must use &lt;mdWrap&gt; to encompass a record that conforms 
					to Dublin Core schema specifications.  This record will describe the complete object, 
					rather than a component part.  Other descriptive metadata sections may appear; 
					it is recommended, though not required, that they conform to a descriptive 
					metadata schema endorsed by the METS Editorial Board.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec3">
				<p>The primary &lt;dmdSec&gt; element must have an ID attribute with the value "DC".  
					The &lt;mdWrap&gt; element must have a MIMETYPE, LABEL and MDTYPE attribute value, 
					with the LABEL and MDTYPE attribute value being "DC".</p>
			</requirement>
		</dmdSec>
		<amdSec>
			<requirement ID="amdSec1">
				<p>METS documents may but need not contain oand and only one &lt;amdSec&gt;
					element. This &lt;amdSec&gt; may but need not contain one or more
					&lt;techMD&gt; elements, &lt;sourceMD&gt; elements,
					&lt;rightsMD&gt; elements and/or &lt;digiprovMD&gt; elements.
				</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="amdSec2">
				<p>It is recommended, though not required, that &lt;rightsMD&gt;, &lt;techMD&gt;, 
					&lt;sourceMD&gt; and &lt;digiprovMD&gt; sections employ a schema endorsed by 
					the METS Editorial Board, such as	METSRights.</p>
			</requirement>
		</amdSec>
		<fileSec>
			<requirement ID="fileSec1">
				<p>METS documents must contain a &lt;fileSec&gt; element.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec2">
				<p>The &lt;fileSec&gt; of a conforming METS document must contain a parent
					&lt;fileGrp&gt; for each file format/use represented by the content
					files. Each of these &lt;fileGrp&gt; elements may but need not
					contain subsidiary &lt;fileGrp&gt; elements representing subgroups of
					the content files.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec3">
				<p>Each &lt;file&gt; represented in the &lt;fileSec&gt; must have an ID attribute value 
					that is unique within the METS instance for use in linking from the &lt;structMap&gt;.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec4" RELATEDMAT="vc1">
				<p>Each &lt;file&gt; represented in the &lt;fileSec&gt; must have an
					associated USE attribute. The USE attribute may be expressed directly at the
					&lt;file&gt; element level. Alternately, however, the USE attribute may
					be expressed in conjunction with the &lt;fileGrp&gt; that is the
					immediate parent of a &lt;file&gt; element; in this case it is taken to
					pertain to all &lt;file&gt; elements in the &lt;fileGrp&gt;.  The value must conform
					to the list given in the controlled vocabularies sections above.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec5">
				<p>If a &lt;fileGrp&gt; contains more than one &lt;file&gt; element, it is recommended, 
					but not required that each &lt;file&gt; have an associated GROUPID attribute.  In cases 
					where there is only one &lt;file&gt; contained in a &lt;fileGrp&gt;, the GROUPID attribute 
					is not necessary.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec6">
				<p>If a raw ASCII text transcription file exists for a scanned document, it must be included 
					within the &lt;fileSec&gt; using &lt;file&gt;&lt;FContent&gt;&lt;xmlData&gt; and must have 
					the element &lt;transcription&gt; as the wrapping element for the content.</p>
			</requirement>
		</fileSec>
		<structMap>
			<requirement ID="structMap1">
				<p>A conforming METS document must contain one and only one &lt;structMap&gt;.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap2">
				<p>It is recommended that each &lt;div&gt; element have an associated ID attribute .</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap3">
				<p>A &lt;structMap&gt; must have a top-level &lt;div&gt; element that represents the 
					object as a whole.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap4">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; element may but need not directly contain one and only one &lt;fptr&gt; 
					elements. (In other words, a &lt;div&gt; may or may not have content files directly associated
					with it.)   If a &lt;div&gt; does not directly govern an &lt;fptr&gt; element, then it must contain
					at least 1 descendant &lt;div&gt; element with associated content.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap5">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; can have at most one content file directly associated with it - and hence at most
					one child &lt;fptr&gt; element.  If multiple manifestations of the same content are available (for
					example, a thumbnail image and two service images of different resolutions), each of these
					manifestations must be represented by a discrete &lt;div&gt; element.</p>				
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap6">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; element cannot directly contain both a &lt;div&gt; element and an &lt;fptr&gt; 
					element as immediate children.  A &lt;div&gt; element may have one or more &lt;div&gt; 
					elements as immediate children; or it may have a single &lt;fptr&gt; element as an immediate
					child element.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap7">
				<p>Each &lt;div&gt; that does not directly contain a &lt;fptr&gt; element must include a 
					LABEL attribute value.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap8">
				<p>If a &lt;div&gt; directly contains a &lt;fptr&gt;, it must have an 
					associated TYPE attribute and must not have associated LABEL or ORDER attributes.</p>
			</requirement>
		</structMap>
	</structural_requirements>
	<technical_requirements>
		<content_files>
			<requirement ID="content1">
				<p>Image content files referenced from or included in conforming METS documents must
					be of one of the following types: GIF, JPG, JP2, PNG or TIFF.  Please consult the CDL Guidelines 
					for Digital Images (http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/guidelines/bpgimages/) for more 
					information about profiles, resolution, encoding, and other format issues.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="content2">
				<p>Text transcriptions, if they appear, must be raw, unstructured ASCII text.</p>
			</requirement>
		</content_files>
	</technical_requirements>
	<tool>
		<agency>California Digital Library</agency>
		<URI>http://sourceforge.net/projects/seventrain</URI>
		<description><p>This XSL-based transformation package converts CONTENTdm XML exports into METS
			objects conforming to this profile.</p></description>
	</tool>
	<Appendix ID="Ex1" NUMBER="1" LABEL="7train METS Profile Example 1">
		<mets:mets 
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" 
		    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
		    xmlns:mets="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
		    xmlns:rts="http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights/"
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="	http://www.loc.gov/METS/ 
						http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd" 
		    OBJID="ark:/13030/pf0z00zz00"
		    LABEL="Male performer in female dress, dancing on stage, San Quentin Little Olympics Field Meet" 
		    TYPE="image" 
		    PROFILE="http://ark.cdlib.org/mets/profiles/7trainProfile.xml">
			<mets:metsHdr CREATEDATE="2006-02-06T15:25:06.723-08:00" 
				LASTMODDATE="2006-04-12T08:35:51.731-06:50" RECORDSTATUS="NEW" ID="d314">
				<mets:agent ROLE="EDITOR" TYPE="ORGANIZATION">
					<mets:name>California Digital Library</mets:name>
					<mets:note>Record created by conversion of CONTENTdm XML metadata</mets:note>
					<mets:note>Created using 7train</mets:note>
				</mets:agent>
				<mets:altRecordID>csrcl_005</mets:altRecordID>
			</mets:metsHdr>
			<mets:dmdSec ID="DC" CREATED="2006-02-06T15:25:06.723-08:00">
				<mets:mdWrap MIMETYPE="text/xml" MDTYPE="DC" LABEL="DC">
					<mets:xmlData>
						<dc:identifier>csrcl_005</dc:identifier>
						<dc:title>Male performer in female dress, dancing on stage, San Quentin Little 
							Olympics Field Meet, 1930 [photograph]</dc:title>
						<dc:creator>Unknown</dc:creator>
						<dc:subject>California State Prison at San Quentin</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Marin County (Calif.)</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Track and field</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Athletics</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Prisoners 1910-1940</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Olympic Club (San Francisco, Calif.)</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Recreation -- California -- Marin County</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Cross-dressers</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Musicians</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Male dancers</dc:subject>
						<dc:type>Image</dc:type>
						<dc:type>Photographs</dc:type>
						<dc:format>1 photographic print, b&amp;w ; 11 x 16 cm.</dc:format>
						<dc:publisher>Marin County Free Library.  Anne T. Kent California Room</dc:publisher>
						<dc:rights>unknown</dc:rights>
						<dc:subject>Stanley, Leo L. (Leo Leonidas), 1886-1976</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Olympic Club (San Francisco, Calif.)</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>California State Prison at San Quentin</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>California State Prison at San Quentin--Little Olympics</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Holohan, James B.</dc:subject>
						<dc:subject>Johnston, James A., 1874-</dc:subject>
						<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
						<dc:identifier>A.1925.001.004</dc:identifier>
						<dc:description>Beginning in 1913, an annual track and field meet know as the "Little Olympics" 
							was held at San Quentin Prison on a holiday such as Thanksgiving Day or Admission Day, 
							under the auspices of the San Francisco Olympic Club. This was a day when prison rules 
							were suspended and prisoners were allowed to participate in athletic and stage events, 
							cheered on by their fellow inmates. The meet was the brainchild of reformist warden, 
							James A. Johnston, who was a member of the Olympic Club. After Olympic Club 
							sponsorship ended, athletic events and field meets inspired by the "Little Olympics" 
							continued to form part of prison life.  In addition to traditional track and field events, 
							the "Little Olympics" also included such non-traditional activities as a tug-of-war between 
							teams recruited from the San Quentin mill and shops, a pie-eating contest, sack races, 
							clowns, and musical and stage entertainment.  This photograph is from the 17th annual 
							field meet held at San Quentin in 1930 when James B. Holohan was the acting warden. 
							Olympic Club member, Frank G. O'Kane, was Master of Ceremonies. The 
							entertainers depicted are San Quentin inmates; the cross-dressers were a popular 
							attraction.</dc:description>
						<dc:contributor>Stanley, Leo L. (Leo Leonidas), 1886-1976</dc:contributor>
					</mets:xmlData>
				</mets:mdWrap>
			</mets:dmdSec>
			<mets:dmdSec ID="ead">
				<mets:mdRef LOCTYPE="URL" MDTYPE="EAD" ID="pfnullxxxx" LABEL="EAD Label" xlink:href="http://www.oac.cdlib.org/findaid/ark:/13030/pfnullxxxx"/>
			</mets:dmdSec>
			<mets:dmdSec ID="repo">
				<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="DC" MIMETYPE="text/xml" LABEL="Repository">
					<mets:xmlData>
						<dc:title>Marin County Free Library</dc:title>
						<dc:identifier>non-ark:/13030/pfnullnull</dc:identifier>
						<dc:identifier>http://www.co.marin.ca.us/library/</dc:identifier>
					</mets:xmlData>
				</mets:mdWrap>
			</mets:dmdSec>
			<mets:amdSec ID="d287">
				<mets:rightsMD ID="d298">
					<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="OTHER" OTHERMDTYPE="METSRights">
						<mets:xmlData>
							<rts:RightsDeclarationMD RIGHTSCATEGORY="OTHER" OTHERCATEGORYTYPE="UNKNOWN">
								<rts:RightsDeclaration>Rights status unknown</rts:RightsDeclaration>
								<rts:RightsHolder>
									<rts:RightsHolderName>unknown</rts:RightsHolderName>
								</rts:RightsHolder>
								<rts:Context CONTEXTCLASS="GENERAL PUBLIC">
									<rts:Constraints CONSTRAINTTYPE="RE-USE">
										<rts:ConstraintDescription>For uses of text or images from this document 
											which extend beyond fair use (such as publication or inclusion in 
											commercial online resources), requests for permission must be 
											submitted in writing to: Marin County Free Library, San Rafael, CA  94903</rts:ConstraintDescription>
									</rts:Constraints>
								</rts:Context>
							</rts:RightsDeclarationMD>
						</mets:xmlData>
					</mets:mdWrap>
				</mets:rightsMD>
			</mets:amdSec>
			<mets:fileSec ID="d317">
				<mets:fileGrp USE="thumbnail image">
					<mets:file ID="d3e2926" GROUPID="front">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/images/thumbnails/pf0z00zz00_img01.gif"/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="d3e2929" GROUPID="back">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/images/thumbnails/pf0z00zz00_img02.gif"/>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
				<mets:fileGrp USE="reference image">
					<mets:file ID="d3e2936" GROUPID="front">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/images/reference/pf0z00zz00_img01.jpg"/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="d3e2939" GROUPID="back">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/images/reference/pf0z00zz00_img02.jpg"/>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
				<mets:fileGrp USE="archive image">
					<mets:file ID="d3e2946" GROUPID="front">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/dpr/pf0z00zz00_img01.tif"/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="d3e2949" GROUPID="back">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="http://content.cdlib.org/dpr/pf0z00zz00_img02.tif"/>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
				<mets:fileGrp USE="transcription">
					<mets:file ID="d3e2951" GROUPID="front">
						<mets:FContent>
							<mets:xmlData>
								<transcription>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit, sed diam nonummy nibh
									euismod tincidunt ut laoreet dolore magna aliquam erat volutpat. Ut wisi enim ad minim veniam,
									quis nostrud exerci tation ullamcorper suscipit lobortis nisl ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat.
									Duis autem vel eum iriure dolor in hendrerit in vulputate velit esse molestie consequat, vel illum
									dolore eu feugiat nulla facilisis at vero eros et accumsan et iusto odio dignissim qui blandit
									praesent luptatum zzril delenit augue duis dolore te feugait nulla facilisi. Nam liber tempor cum
									soluta nobis eleifend option congue nihil imperdiet doming id quod mazim placerat facer possim
									assum. Typi non habent claritatem insitam; est usus legentis in iis qui facit eorum claritatem.</transcription>
							</mets:xmlData>
						</mets:FContent>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
			</mets:fileSec>
			<mets:structMap>
				<mets:div ID="d411" LABEL="Male performer in female dress, dancing on stage, San Quentin Little Olympics Field Meet" DMDID="DC">
					<mets:div ID="d415" LABEL="front">
						<mets:div ID="d417" TYPE="thumbnail image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2926"/>
						</mets:div>
						<mets:div ID="d419" TYPE="reference image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2936"/>
						</mets:div>
						<mets:div ID="d421" TYPE="archive image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2946"/>
						</mets:div>
						<mets:div ID="d423" TYPE="transcription">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2951"/>
						</mets:div>
					</mets:div>
					<mets:div ID="d426" LABEL="back">
						<mets:div ID="d427" TYPE="thumbnail image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2929"/>
						</mets:div>
						<mets:div ID="d429" TYPE="reference image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2939"/>
						</mets:div>
						<mets:div ID="d431" TYPE="archive image">
							<mets:fptr FILEID="d3e2949"/>
						</mets:div>
					</mets:div>
				</mets:div>
			</mets:structMap>
		</mets:mets>
	</Appendix>
</METS_Profile>
