<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<METS_Profile xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/            http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profile_docs/mets.profile.v1-2.xsd">
	<URI LOCTYPE="URL">http://www.loc.gov/mets/profiles/00000022.xml</URI>
	<title>METS Profile Version MANUSCRIPTS</title>
	<abstract>This profile governs METS instance documents of Whitman authored manuscripts intended
		for submission to other digital library and centers for digital humanities research as well
		as METS documents intended for reference use and dissemination to internal and external
		documents within the archive. The digital content governed by the METS documents conforming
		to this profile must be of the type or combination of types including: images and tei-based
		structured text. Source materials whose METS encoded digital versions would be covered by
		this profile exclusively include manuscripts authored by Walt Whitman. This profile covers
		reformatted-digital materials intended for general reference and scholarly use.</abstract>
	<date>2007-01-30T00:00:00</date>
	<contact>
		<name>Stacey Berry</name>
		<address>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities, University of Nebraska–Lincoln, 319
			Love Library/P.O. Box 884100, Lincoln NE, 68588-4100 </address>
		<phone>402.472.4547</phone>
		<email>cdrh@unl.edu</email>
	</contact>
	<related_profile RELATIONSHIP="parents" URI=""/>
	<related_profile RELATIONSHIP="" URI=""/>
	<extension_schema ID="ext1">
		<name>MODS</name>
		<URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-1.xsd</URI>
		<context>mets/dmdSec/mdWrap/xmlData</context>
		<note>While the schema referenced above represents v.3.1 of MODS, all v.3.x MODS schemas are
			largely backwards compatible with previous incremental releases of version 3. METS
			documents using any version 3 MODS schema are accommodated by this profile.</note>
	</extension_schema>
	<extension_schema ID="ext2">
		<name>NISO MIX</name>
		<URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/mix/mix.xsd</URI>
		<context>mets/amdSec/techMD/mdWrap/xmlData</context>
		<note>Used for technical metadata about image content files.This profile supports both the
			existing version 1.5 of the schema as well as version 2 as soon as this becomes
			available.</note>
	</extension_schema>
	<extension_schema ID="ext3">
		<name>textmd</name>
		<URI>http://dlib.nyu.edu/METS/textmd.xsd</URI>
		<context>mets/amdSec/techMD/mdWrap/xmlData</context>
		<note>Used for technical metadata about text content files.</note>
	</extension_schema>
	<extension_schema ID="ext4">
		<name>METSRights</name>
		<URI>http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights.xsd</URI>
		<context>mets/amdSec/rightsMD/mdWrap/xmlData</context>
		<note>Used for rights information about original and digital materials.</note>
	</extension_schema>
	<description_rules>
		<p>All applications of the MODS schema in conforming METS documents should follow the MODS
			User Guidelines published by Library of Congress' Network Development and MARC Standards
			Office. (http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-userguide.html). </p>
	</description_rules>
	<controlled_vocabularies>
		<vocabulary ID="vc1">
			<name>&lt;mets&gt; TYPE attribute values</name>
			<maintenance_agency>Walt Whitman Archive</maintenance_agency>
			<URI>
				<!--we do not yet have a web space dedicated to these kinds of guidelines-->
			</URI>
			<values>
				<value>Manuscript</value>
			</values>
			<context>
				<p>mets/@TYPE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>This profile specifies the required vocabulary for the TYPE attribute value on
					the root &lt;mets&gt; element. It is required that this attribute
					appear.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
		<vocabulary ID="vc6">
			<name>&lt;dmdSec:mdWrap&gt; MIMETYPE attribute values</name>
			<maintenance_agency>Walt Whitman Archive</maintenance_agency>
			<URI/>
			<values>
				<value>text/xml</value>
			</values>
			<context>
				<p>DMDSEC/MDWRAP/@MIMETYPE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>This profile specifies the required vocabulary for the MIMETYPE attribute value
					on the &lt;dmdSec:mdWrap&gt; element. It is required that this attribute
					appear.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
		<vocabulary ID="vc2">
			<name>&lt;techMD:mdWrap&gt; MDTYPE/OTHERMDTYPE Attribute Values</name>
			<maintenance_agency>Walt Whitman Archive</maintenance_agency>
			<values>
				<value>OTHER</value>
				<value>textMD</value>
				<value>NISO MIX</value>
			</values>
			<context>
				<p>TECHMD/MDWRAP/@MDTYPE</p>
				<p>TECHMD/MDWRAP/@OTHERMDTYPE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>This profile specifies MDTYPE attribute value on the
					&lt;techMD:mdWrap&gt; element. If the MDTYPE="OTHER", then a value must
					be declared for OTHERMDTYPE from the listed attribute values.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
		<vocabulary ID="vc3">
			<name>METS &lt;fileGrp&gt; USE Attribute Values</name>
			<maintenance_agency>Walt Whitman Archive</maintenance_agency>
			<values>
				<value>transcription</value>
				<value>reference image</value>
			</values>
			<context>
				<p>mets/fileSec/fileGrp/@USE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>These are the supported values for &lt;fileGrp&gt; USE attributes in METS
					documents implementing this profile. They are intended mainly to help
					presentation programs know how they should treat particular content files. In
					particular, they should help a presentation program distinguish between content
					files that are text or image based. They can also provide a presentation program
					with information that can help it or the end user decide what is the most
					appropriate content file for a particular purpose when this information is not
					apparent from the content file's MIME type. For example, the USE attribute can
					help identify TEI encoded files and to distinguish these from other structured
					text files. The individual USE attribute values are defined below.</p>
				<p>&quot;transcription&quot; and &quot;reference image&quot; are
					appropriate values to describe the intended use of manuscript image and
					corresponding TEI transcription files encoded according to TEI rules that make
					up digital objects.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
		<vocabulary ID="vc5">
			<name>METS &lt;structMap&gt; div TYPE Attribute Values</name>
			<maintenance_agency>Walt Whitman Archive</maintenance_agency>
			<values>
				<value>manuscript</value>
				<value>page</value>
			</values>
			<context>
				<p>mets/structMap/div/@TYPE</p>
			</context>
			<description>
				<p>These are the supported values for &lt;structMap&gt; div TYPE attributes
					in METS documents implementing this profile. They are intended mainly to help
					presentation programs know how they should treat particular content files. In
					particular, they should help a presentation program distinguish the relationship
					between manuscript pages.</p>
				<p>&quot;manuscript&quot; is the appropriate value to describe the highest
					level div pointing to the manuscript digital object as a whole, and
					&quot;page&quot; is the appropriate value to describe the individual
					page references that constitute the manuscript digital object as a whole.</p>
			</description>
		</vocabulary>
	</controlled_vocabularies>
	<structural_requirements>
		<metsRootElement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot1">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt; element must include an OBJID attribute value
					containing a valid Whitman Archive Manuscript Tracking Number and uniquely
					identifying the digital object represented by the METS document.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot2" RELATEDMAT="vc1">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt; element requires a TYPE attribute value. This
					profile specifies only one vocabulary for the TYPE attribute: Manuscript.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsRoot3">
				<p>The root &lt;mets&gt; element must include a PROFILE attribute value.
					mets_profile_MANUSCRIPT.xml is the current standard profile of reference for all
					Whitman Archive METS files for manuscript digital objects. </p>
			</requirement>
		</metsRootElement>
		<metsHdr>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr1">
				<p>Conforming METS documents must contain a metsHdr element.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="metsHdr2">
				<p>The &lt;metsHdr&gt; element must include the CREATEDATE attribute value.
					It must also include the LASTMODDATE attribute value if this does not coincide
					with the CREATEDATE.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>The &lt;metsHdr&gt; element must include a child &lt;agent&gt;
					element identifying the person or institution responsible for creating the METS
					object. The &lt;agent&gt; element must include the ROLE attribute with
					the following possible values: CREATOR, EDITOR, [...].</p>
			</requirement>
		</metsHdr>
		<dmdSec>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec1">
				<p>Conforming METS documents must contain one or more &lt;dmdSec&gt;
					elements. Each &lt;dmdSec&gt; must contain an &lt;mdWrap&gt;</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec2">
				<p>Conforming METS documents must contain a unique ID for each
					&lt;dmdSec&gt; (dmd1, dmd2, etc).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec3" RELATEDMAT="ext1">
				<p>At least one version of any descriptive metadata appearing in
					&lt;mdWrap&gt; elements in a compliant document must conform to the MODS
					schema.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="dmdSec4" RELATEDMAT="vc6">
				<p>Each &lt;mdWrap&gt; element must contain the attributes ID, MDTYPE, and
					MIMETYPE. The ID attributes must reflect the MDTYPE in consecutive numerical
					order. If the MDTYPE attribute for the first mdWrap is, for example, MODS, then
					the ID attribute for that mdWrap section will be MODS1. If there are more than
					one MDTYPE="MODS" sections, then they should be numbered accordingly in the ID
					attribute (MODS1, MODS2, MODS3, etc.). The MIMETYPE attribute should conform to
					the controlled vocabulary contained within this profile and will in almost every
					circumstance be text/xml.</p>
			</requirement>
		</dmdSec>
		<amdSec>
			<requirement ID="amdSec1">
				<p>Conforming METS documents must contain only one &lt;amdSec&gt; element.
					This section must contain one or more of each of the following elements:
					&lt;techMD&gt;, &lt;rightsMD&gt;, and
				&lt;sourceMD&lt;.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="techMD1">
				<p>Conforming METS documents for manuscripts must contain two &lt;techMD&gt;
					elements. One element provides technical metadata for the TEI transcription and
					the other for images. Each &lt;techMD&gt; element must contain a unique
					ID attribute value (tmd1, tmd2, etc). </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="techMD2" RELATEDMAT="vc2">
				<p>Each &lt;techMD&gt; element must contain an &lt;mdWrap&gt;
					element and corresponding MDTYPE/OTHERMDTYPE attribute. The MDTYPE/OTHERMDTYPE
					attributes must conform to the controlled vocabulary contained within this
					profile. MDTYPE/OTHERMDTYPE attributes must describe the type of file as either
					text based (textMD) or image based (NISO MIX).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="techMD3" RELATEDMAT="ext2">
				<p>&lt;techMD&gt; elements pertaining to image content files must contain
					&lt;xmlData&gt; conforming to the MIX schema.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="techMD4" RELATEDMAT="ext3">
				<p>&lt;techMD&gt; elements pertaining to text content files must contain
					&lt;xmlData&gt; conforming to the textMD schema.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="rightsMD1">
				<p>One &lt;rightsMD&lt; element must specify those rights declared for the
					thematic research collection. Additional &lt;rightsMD&lt; elements must
					specify those rights retained by the holding institution(s). Each must have a
					unique ID attribute value (rights1, rights2, and etc.). </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="rightsMD2">
				<p>&lt;rightsMD&gt; elements must contain &lt;xmlData&gt; conforming
					to the METS Rights schema. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="sourceMD1">
				<p>Each &lt;sourceMD&lt; element must identify the repository location
					information for the original material represented by the digital object. A
					separate &lt;sourceMD&lt; element must identify the Whitman Archive as
					the repository location for the digital object. Each &lt;sourceMD&lt;
					element must include a unique ID attribute value (smd1, smd2, etc). </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="sourceMD2">
				<p>The &lt;sourceMD&lt; must include an &lt;mdRef&lt; element with
					the following attributes: LOCTYPE="URL", MDTYPE="EAD", xlink:href, and XPTR.
					These attributes point to the location of the corresponding descriptive metadata
					within the Whitman Archive and Holding Repository EAD files.</p>
			</requirement>
		</amdSec>
		<fileSec>
			<requirement ID="fileSec1">
				<p>Conforming METS documents for this profile must contain a
					&lt;fileSec&gt;. The &lt;fileSec&gt; of a conforming METS
					document must contain a parent &lt;fileGrp&gt; for each file format/use
					represented by the content files. For example, the &lt;fileSec&gt; of a
					typical METS document implementing this profile will contain one
					&lt;fileGrp&gt; representing TEI Transcriptions and one
					&lt;fileGrp&gt; representing images. This profile does not support
					nested &lt;fileGrp&gt; elements. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec2" RELATEDMAT="vc3">
				<p>Each &lt;file&gt; represented in the &lt;fileSec&gt; must have an
					associated USE attribute. The USE attribute can be expressed directly at the
					&lt;file&gt; element level. Alternately, the USE attribute may be
					expressed in conjunction with the &lt;fileGrp&gt; that is the immediate
					parent of a &lt;file&gt; element; in this case it is taken to pertain to
					all &lt;file&gt; elements in the &lt;fileGrp&gt;. The
					&lt;file&gt;/&lt;fileGrp&gt; USE attribute values must be drawn
					from the controlled vocaulary for &lt;file&gt;/&lt;fileGrp&gt;
					USE Attribute Values contained within this profile.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec3">
				<p>The &lt;file&gt; elements in a conforming METS document must contain ID
					and SIZE attribute values. They must also contain CREATED attribute values when
					available.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec4">
				<p>Each &lt;file&gt; represented in the &lt;fileSec&gt; must have an
					associated MIMETYPE attribute. This attribute must contain the official Internet
					Standard MIME type value for the content file represented</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec5">
				<p>Each file must be associated with a &lt;techMD&gt; and a
					&lt;rightsMD&gt; element, either via reference from the parent
					&lt;fileGrp&gt; element ADMID attribute value or via reference from the
					&lt;file&gt; element ADMID attribute value.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec6">
				<p>Each &lt;file&gt; element must contain an &lt;FLocat&gt; element
					which specifies the external location of the content file in an xlink:href
					attribute.The &lt;FLocat&gt; element must contain an xlink:href
					attribute, as well as a LOCTYPE attribute indicating the type of href being
					provided. In most cases, the LOCTYPE for manuscript objects will be URL.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="fileSec7">
				<p>This profile supports the use of one and only one &lt;FLocat&gt; element
					in conjunction with each &lt;file&gt; element.</p>
			</requirement>
		</fileSec>
		<structMap>
			<requirement ID="structMap1">
				<p>A conforming METS document must contain one and only one
					&lt;structMap&gt;. This &lt;structMap&gt; must not be empty.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap2">
				<p>A conforming &lt;structMap&gt; must contain a TYPE attribute. METS
					documents conforming to this profile will report the value MIXED for the type
					attribute.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap3">
				<p>Each &lt;div&gt; at the highest level must include a LABEL attribute
					value and a TYPE attribute value.The LABEL attribute should identify the content
					of the material for presentation to the end user. For example, for the highest
					level &lt;div&gt; the LABEL attribute value will be the title of the
					poem. The TYPE attribute value must conform with the controlled TYPE attribute
					vocabulary included in this profile.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap4" RELATEDMAT="dmdSec4">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; element at the highest level must point to one or more
					pertinent &lt;dmdSec&gt; elements via its DMDID attribute value.
					However, the DMDID attribute should only reference ID values declared at the
					&lt;dmdSec&gt; element level, and not IDs at lower levels. For example,
					a &lt;div&gt; DMDID attribute should not reference the ID value of an
					element within the &lt;xmlData&gt; section of a
				&lt;dmdSec&gt;.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap5" RELATEDMAT="sourceMD1">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; element at the highest level must include an ADMID
					attribute to point to corresponding sourceMD IDs pertinent to the content the
					&lt;div&gt; element represents (smd1, smd2, etc.). These sourceMD
					sections point to the external metadata describing that object.</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap6">
				<p>A &lt;div&gt; element at the highest level must contain at least one or
					more &lt;div&gt; elements and one or more &lt;fptr&gt; elements.
					A &lt;div&gt; element at any level may contain one or more
					&lt;div&gt; and/or &lt;fptr&gt; elements. The
					&lt;div&gt; and &lt;fptr&gt; elements must be nested and labeled
					to represent the relationship between individual pieces that constitute the
					object. After the highest level &lt;div&gt; each subsequent
					&lt;div&gt; element must contain both TYPE and LABEL values. The TYPE
					value is always "page." The LABEL value indicates the order of pages (ie: "leaf
					1 recto" and "leaf 1 verso").</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement ID="structMap9">
				<p>Each &lt;area&gt; element must include the following attribute values to
					describe order and relationship between referenced IDs: BEGIN, END, and
				BETYPE.</p>
			</requirement>
		</structMap>
	</structural_requirements>
	<technical_requirements>
		<content_files>
			<requirement>
				<p>All &quot;tei&quot; files must be encoded according to version 1 of the
					"TEI Text Encoding in Libraries: Guidelines for Best Encoding Practices"
					maintained by the Digital Library Federation
					(http://www.diglib.org/standards/tei.htm).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files adhere to ISO-8859-1 character encoding standards maintained by the
					Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (http://www.iana.org/).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files reference stylesheet "Whitman.xsl" </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files reference DTD "whitman.dtd"</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files adhere to current MODS schema maintained by the Library of Congress
					(http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-1.xsd).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files adhere to current NISO MIX standards maintained by the Library of
					Congress (http://www.loc.gov/standards/mix/mix.xsd).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files adhere to current textMD standards maintained by New York University
					(http://dlib.nyu.edu/METS/text.xsd).</p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<p>All files adhere to METSRights schema maintained by Stanford Univeristy
					(http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights.xsd).</p>
			</requirement>
		</content_files>
	</technical_requirements>
	<tool/>
	<Appendix ID="EX1" NUMBER="1" LABEL="Manuscript Example">
		<mets:mets OBJID="yal.00003" xmlns:mets="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
			xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
			xmlns:mix="http://www.loc.gov/mix/"
			xmlns:rights="http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights/"
			xmlns:textMD="http://www.nyu.edu/textMD/"
			xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
			xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS/ http://www.loc.gov/mets/mets.xsd http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-0.xsd http://www.loc.gov/mix/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mix/mix02/mix02.xsd http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights/ http://cosimo.stanford.edu/sdr/metsrights.xsd"
			TYPE="Manuscript" PROFILE="WhitmanArchive_MS_Document_Profile.xml">
			<mets:metsHdr CREATEDATE="2006-04-18T08:47:16">
				<mets:agent ROLE="CREATOR">
					<mets:name>Stacey Berry</mets:name>
				</mets:agent>
			</mets:metsHdr>
			<!-- Descriptive Metadata -->
			<mets:dmdSec ID="dmd1">
				<mets:mdWrap ID="MODS1" MDTYPE="MODS" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
					<mets:xmlData>
						<mods:mods>
							<mods:accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">For rights relating to
								this resource, visit http://www.whitmanarchive.org/fair_use/</mods:accessCondition>
							<mods:genre authority="marc">poetry</mods:genre>
							<mods:identifier type="uri"
								>http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/manuscriptsframeset_files/transcriptions_alt/yal.00003</mods:identifier>
							<mods:recordInfo>
								<mods:recordContentSource authority="OCLC">LDL</mods:recordContentSource>
								<mods:recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2006-09-12</mods:recordCreationDate>
								<mods:languageOfCataloging>
									<mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</mods:languageTerm>
								</mods:languageOfCataloging>
							</mods:recordInfo>
							<mods:typeOfResource manuscript="yes">text</mods:typeOfResource>
							<mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
							<mods:titleInfo>
								<mods:title>Italian Music in Dakota</mods:title>
							</mods:titleInfo>
							<mods:name>
								<mods:role>
									<mods:roleTerm>Author</mods:roleTerm>
								</mods:role>
								<mods:namePart>Whitman, Walt</mods:namePart>
							</mods:name>
							<mods:name>
								<mods:role>
									<mods:roleTerm>Editor</mods:roleTerm>
								</mods:role>
								<mods:namePart>Price, Kenneth M.</mods:namePart>
							</mods:name>
							<mods:name>
								<mods:role>
									<mods:roleTerm>Editor</mods:roleTerm>
								</mods:role>
								<mods:namePart>Folsom, Ed</mods:namePart>
							</mods:name>
							<mods:originInfo>
								<mods:dateIssued keyDate="yes">2003</mods:dateIssued>
								<mods:dateModified>2006-09-02</mods:dateModified>
							</mods:originInfo>
							<mods:physicalDescription>
								<mods:digitalOrigin>reformatted digital</mods:digitalOrigin>
								<mods:internetMediaType>image/jpeg</mods:internetMediaType>
								<mods:internetMediaType>text/xml</mods:internetMediaType>
							</mods:physicalDescription>
							<mods:targetAudience>Whitman scholars</mods:targetAudience>
							<mods:classification authority="lcc">PS3222.I7</mods:classification>

							<mods:relatedItem type="original">

								<mods:location>
									<mods:physicalLocation authority="marcorg">CtY-BR</mods:physicalLocation>
									<mods:physicalLocation>Yale University, Beinecke Rare Book and
										Manuscript Library (New Haven, CT)</mods:physicalLocation>
								</mods:location>
							</mods:relatedItem>
							<mods:subject authority="lcsh">
								<mods:geographic>United States</mods:geographic>
							</mods:subject>
						</mods:mods>

					</mets:xmlData>
				</mets:mdWrap>
			</mets:dmdSec>

			<mets:amdSec>
				<!-- Technical Metadata: Electronic Transcription -->
				<mets:techMD ID="tmd1">
					<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="OTHER" OTHERMDTYPE="textMD">
						<mets:xmlData>
							<textMD:textMD>
								<textMD:markup_basis>XML</textMD:markup_basis>
								<textMD:markup_language>TEI</textMD:markup_language>
							</textMD:textMD>
						</mets:xmlData>
					</mets:mdWrap>
				</mets:techMD>
				<!-- Technical Metadata: JPEG Derivatives -->
				<mets:techMD ID="tmd2">
					<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="NISOIMG">
						<mets:xmlData>
							<mix:mix>
								<mix:BasicImageParameters>
									<mix:Format>
										<mix:MIMEType>image/jpeg</mix:MIMEType>
									</mix:Format>
								</mix:BasicImageParameters>
							</mix:mix>
						</mets:xmlData>
					</mets:mdWrap>
				</mets:techMD>
				<!-- Rights Metadata: Whitman Archive-->
				<mets:rightsMD ID="rights1">
					<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="OTHER" OTHERMDTYPE="METS RIGHTS">
						<mets:xmlData>
							<rights:RightsDeclarationMD>
								<rights:RightsHolder>
									<rights:RightsHolderName>Walt Whitman
									Archive</rights:RightsHolderName>
								</rights:RightsHolder>
								<rights:Context CONTEXTCLASS="GENERAL PUBLIC">
									<rights:Permissions DISCOVER="1"/>
								</rights:Context>
								<rights:Context CONTEXTCLASS="ACADEMIC USER">
									<rights:Permissions DISCOVER="1" COPY="1"/>
								</rights:Context>
							</rights:RightsDeclarationMD>
						</mets:xmlData>
					</mets:mdWrap>
				</mets:rightsMD>

				<!-- Rights Metadata: Yale-->
				<mets:rightsMD ID="rights2">
					<mets:mdWrap MDTYPE="OTHER" OTHERMDTYPE="METS RIGHTS">
						<mets:xmlData>
							<rights:RightsDeclarationMD>
								<rights:RightsHolder>
									<rights:RightsHolderName>Yale University, Beinecke Rare Book and
										Manuscript Library (New Haven, CT)</rights:RightsHolderName>
								</rights:RightsHolder>
								<rights:Context CONTEXTCLASS="GENERAL PUBLIC">
									<rights:Permissions DISCOVER="1"/>
								</rights:Context>
								<rights:Context CONTEXTCLASS="ACADEMIC USER">
									<rights:Permissions DISCOVER="1"/>
								</rights:Context>
							</rights:RightsDeclarationMD>
						</mets:xmlData>
					</mets:mdWrap>
				</mets:rightsMD>

				<!-- Source Descriptive Metadata: Whitman Archive -->
				<mets:sourceMD ID="smd1">
					<mets:mdRef LOCTYPE="URL" MDTYPE="EAD" xlink:href="unionGuide.xml"
						XPTR="//c02[descendant::unitid = 'yal.00003' ]"/>
				</mets:sourceMD>
				<!-- Source Descriptive Metadata: Repository -->
				<mets:sourceMD ID="smd2">
					<mets:mdRef LOCTYPE="URL" MDTYPE="EAD" xlink:href="yal.ead01.xml"
						XPTR="//c02[descendant::unitid = 'yal.00003' ]"/>
				</mets:sourceMD>
			</mets:amdSec>
			<!-- File Section -->
			<mets:fileSec>
				<!-- Transcription -->
				<mets:fileGrp USE="transcription">
					<mets:file ID="FID1" MIMETYPE="text/xml" SIZE="12288"
						CREATED="2006-02-09T12:00:00" ADMID="rights1 tmd1">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
							xlink:href="http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/manuscriptsframeset_files/transcriptions_alt/yal.00003"
						/>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
				<!-- Reference Images -->
				<mets:fileGrp USE="reference image" ADMID="rights2">
					<mets:file ID="FID2" MIMETYPE="image/jpg" SIZE="99192" ADMID="tmd2">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
							xlink:href="http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/figures/yal.00003.001_large.jpg"
						/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="FID3" MIMETYPE="image/jpg" SIZE="74065" ADMID="tmd2">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
							xlink:href="http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/figures/yal.00003.002_large.jpg"
						/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="FID4" MIMETYPE="image/jpg" SIZE="174863" ADMID="tmd2">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
							xlink:href="http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/figures/yal.00003.003_large.jpg"
						/>
					</mets:file>
					<mets:file ID="FID5" MIMETYPE="image/jpg" SIZE="149709" ADMID="tmd2">
						<mets:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
							xlink:href="http://www.whitmanarchive.org/manuscripts/figures/yal.00003.004_large.jpg"
						/>
					</mets:file>
				</mets:fileGrp>
			</mets:fileSec>
			<!-- Structure Map -->
			<mets:structMap TYPE="mixed">
				<mets:div TYPE="manuscript" LABEL="Italian Music in Dakota" ADMID="smd1 smd2"
					DMDID="MODS1">
					<mets:fptr FILEID="FID1"/>
					<mets:div TYPE="page" LABEL="leaf 1 recto">
						<mets:fptr>
							<mets:area FILEID="FID1" BEGIN="leaf01r" END="leaf01v" BETYPE="IDREF"/>
						</mets:fptr>
						<mets:fptr FILEID="FID2"/>
					</mets:div>
					<mets:div TYPE="page" LABEL="leaf 1 verso">
						<mets:fptr>
							<mets:area FILEID="FID1" BEGIN="leaf01v" BETYPE="IDREF"/>
						</mets:fptr>
						<mets:fptr FILEID="FID3"/>
					</mets:div>
					<mets:div TYPE="page" LABEL="leaf 2 recto">
						<mets:fptr>
							<mets:area FILEID="FID3" BEGIN="leaf02r" END="leaf02v" BETYPE="IDREF"/>
						</mets:fptr>
						<mets:fptr FILEID="FID4"/>
					</mets:div>
					<mets:div TYPE="page" LABEL="leaf 2 verso">
						<mets:fptr>
							<mets:area FILEID="FID4" BEGIN="leaf02v" BETYPE="IDREF"/>
						</mets:fptr>
					</mets:div>
				</mets:div>
			</mets:structMap>
		</mets:mets>
	</Appendix>
</METS_Profile>
