<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="echoProfile2html.xsl" ?>

<!-- 
    ********************************************************************************
    MasterMETSProfile.xml
    
    Author:
    Bill Ingram (UIUC)
    
    **********************************************************************************
-->
<METS_Profile xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profile_docs/mets.profile.v1-2.xsd">

	<URI LOCTYPE="URL">http://www.loc.gov/mets/profiles/00000029.xml</URI>

	<title>ECHO Dep METS Profile for Master METS Documents</title>

	<abstract>The primary focus of this profile is to enable the preservation of digital content as
		it is moved in and out of digital repositories. Its purpose is to specify how to encode an
		ECHODep "Master METS" document used for aggregating subordinate ECHODep METS documents,
		which capture the state of a digital preservation package before and after it is submitted
		into, and later disseminated out of, a digital repository. Master METS documents that
		conform to this profile will reference their subordinate METS documents via the METS Pointer
		(mptr) element in the METS structMap. Conforming ECHODep preservation packages will contain
		exactly one Master METS document and at least one other subordinate METS document. Each time
		a package is ingested into and later disseminated out of a repository, a new subordinate
		METS document will be created that reflects the current state of the preservation package,
		and a new mptr to that document will be added to the structMap section of the Master METS
		document. </abstract>

	<date>2009-11-17T10:00:00Z</date>

	<contact>
		<name>Bill Ingram</name>
		<institution>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Grainger Engineering Library
			Information Center </institution>
		<address>1301 W. Springfield Ave., Urbana, IL, 61801</address>
		<phone>(217) 244-7809</phone>
		<email>wingram2@uiuc.edu</email>
	</contact>
	
	<related_profile URI="http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profiles/00000015.html" RELATIONSHIP="References"
		>ECHO Dep Generic METS Profile for Preservation and Digital Repository
		Interoperability</related_profile>

	<extension_schema>
		<name>PREMIS Preservation Metadata Schema: Object</name>
		<URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/v1/Object-v1-1.xsd</URI>
		<context>PREMIS Object elements occur embedded in the techMD section. Each file or bitstream
			which occurs in the file section must have a corresponding PREMIS Object in a techMD
			section. METS sections which correspond to PREMIS representations, such as a structMap
			element or the METS file overall, may also have an associated PREMIS object
			element.</context>
	</extension_schema>

	<description_rules>
		<head>Purpose of this Profile</head>
		<p>The purpose of an ECHODep "Master METS" document is to aggregate subordinate ECHODep METS
			documents, each of which represents a digital preservation package at a single point in
			time. A digital preservation package will typically be made up of a set of files that
			represents a single intellectual entity as defined by the community of practice for
			which the intellectual entity applies. For example, in one community of practice the
			intellectual entity of interest may be a web site, but in a different community of
			practice the intellectual entity of interest may be an individual web page. Preservation
			of these packages may refer to short-term interoperability as the digital package is
			moved between two different repositories, or long-term preservation of the package and
			its history as it exists in various repositories for long periods of time and undergoes
			various "preservation actions" such as fixity checks, normalizations, or format
			migrations. Each time the package is moved between repositories, a new subordinate METS
			document should be generated that represents the state of the package at that point in
			time. The Master METS document serves to collect this succession of subordinate ECHODep
			METS files in order to capture the history of the digital preservation package
			throughout its life-cycle. </p>

		<head>Potential Usage Scenario</head>
		<p>A potential usage scenario might be a digital preservation package that is to be ingested
			into DSpace. Before the package is submitted to the repository, assuming this is the
			beginning of the package life-cycle, the Master METS document will reference a single
			subordinate METS file representing the package in its original state. Once ingested, the
			package will exist in DSpace for some period of time during which changes to the
			preservation package might occur. These changes could range in consequence from simple
			revisions to the descriptive metadata, such as the addition of new subject terms or the
			addition of an abstract, to more severe modifications, such as the addition, deletion,
			or renaming of the package's content files or bitstreams. If the package's content files
			are renamed or deleted while under the custody of DSpace, the references to these files
			from the original subordinate ECHODep METS document will be broken. Likewise, if
			additional files are added to the package while in DSpace, the original subordinate
			ECHODep METS file will not make reference to these newly created files. To reflect the
			changes to the preservation package contents that might have occurred while inside the
			repository, a new subordinate ECHODep METS file will need to be generated once the
			package is exported from DSpace, and a pointer to the new subordinate ECHODep METS file
			added to the package's Master METS document. </p>
		<p>After the package is exported from DSpace, it may go on to be ingested into an EPrints or
			Fedora repository, in which case another subordinate ECHODep METS file will be created,
			and a new pointer added to the Master METS file before and after it is submitted into,
			and later disseminated out of, the next repository. At any time throughout the
			life-cycle of the preservation package, the Master METS document may be consulted by
			human or computer applications interested in the history of the package, in addition to
			its current representation. If used in conjunction with the ECHODep Hub and Spoke
			Framework Tool Suite, it will be expected that the Master METS document will contain a
			pointer to at least one subordinate ECHODep METS file, and will likewise expect the METS
			pointer with the most recent timestamp to represent the preservation package in its most
			recently-observed state. When changes are made to the package via our tool suite, they
			will be reflected automatically in the Master METS document. </p>

		<head>METS Identifier</head>
		<p>Each Master METS document must be assigned a persistent and globally unique identifier.
			The only requirement for these identifiers is that they should conform to a
			widely-accepted standard identifier scheme, and they must be locally resolvable; that
			is, the local system must be able to retrieve its local representation of the package
			using only this identifier. It is desirable that these identifiers also be globally
			resolvable. However, global resolution is not defined. Acceptable identifier schemes
			include: OCLC Purls, CNRI Handles, DOIs, and others. </p>
		<p>As this unique identifier is assumed to be the primary identifier for the METS instance,
			it must be recorded in the OBJID attribute of the mets element. It is assumed that the
			OBJID will be assigned at the time the METS file is completed and therefore the
			CREATEDATE attribute must be the date on which the unique identifier was assigned to the
			object. </p>

		<head>PREMIS Identifiers</head>
		<p>All PREMIS object identifiers must be assigned the relative URL of the file to which they
			refer. This URL value will be the same as the href attribute for the mptr element that
			references that same subordinate ECHODep METS file from the Master METS structural map. </p>

		<head>Descriptive Metadata</head>
		<p>This profile assumes that all descriptive metadata for the preservation package will be
			contained in subordinate ECHODep METS documents. As changes in the descriptive metadata
			occur during the life-cycle of the package, they will be reflected in new generations of
			the subordinate METS documents. </p>

		<head>Structural Map</head>
		<p>All Master METS documents will have a simple structMap element that lists the subordinate
			ECHODep METS files for the preservation package. Each subordinate ECHODep METS file is
			referenced via an mptr element with the relative URL to the subordinate file as its href
			attribute. </p>

		<head>Rules for the XML</head>
		<p> Every METS XML file conforming to this profile must be UTF-8 encoded Unicode. </p>
		<p> Every METS XML file conforming to this profile must begin with the standard XML
			declaration: </p>
		<p> &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;. </p>

		<head>Date Values</head>
		<p>Unless otherwise specified (or constrained by the XML Schema) all date values must
			conform to the W3C-DTF format with a granularity of at least days, such as YYYY-MM-DD.
			Finer granularities are acceptable, such as YYYY-MM-DDTHH:MM:SS, but lesser
			granularities are not acceptable, such as YYYY-MM or YYYY. Note that all date attributes
			specified in the METS profile itself require the xsd:dateTime format which is
			YYYY-MM-DDTHH:MM:SS with an optional time zone indicator.</p>
	</description_rules>

	<controlled_vocabularies>
		<vocabulary>
			<description><p>None</p></description>
		</vocabulary>
	</controlled_vocabularies>
	<structural_requirements>
		<metsRootElement>
			<requirement>
				<head>OBJID</head>
				<p>The OBJID attribute must be the primary, persistent, and globally unique
					identifier for the file. This attribute is required; all METS files which are
					conformant to this profile must have a persistent and globally unique
					identifier, unless they are Submission Information Packages that will be
					assigned an identifier upon ingestion. </p>
				<p>The identifier for a Master METS document will always be the same as the
					identifier for its most current subordinate ECHODep METS file. When a new
					subordinate ECHODep METS file is created for the package, the primary identifier
					for the Master METS document will be need to be reassigned accordingly, and the
					old identifier must be listed as an altRecordID in the metsHdr. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<head>LABEL</head>
				<p>The LABEL attribute must contain a human-readable title string that would be
					suitable for distinguishing the METS document from others when a person is
					browsing through a list of METS documents. This value could be a title element
					or variation thereof taken from the dmdSec. This attribute is required. </p>
				<p>As with OBJIDs, the LABEL for a Master METS document will always be the same as
					the LABEL for its most current subordinate ECHODep METS file. When a new
					subordinate ECHODep METS file is created for the package, the LABEL attribute
					for the Master METS document will need to be reassigned accordingly. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<head>PROFILE</head>
				<p> The PROFILE attribute must contain the URI assigned to this profile when it was
					registered with the Library or Congress. The value is
					&lt;http://www.loc.gov/mets/profiles/00000???.xml&gt;. This attribute is
					required. </p>
			</requirement>
		</metsRootElement>
		<metsHdr>
			<requirement>
				<head>CREATEDATE</head>
				<p> This date must be the date on which the METS document was assigned its first
					persistent, globally unique identifier, even if the actual file itself was
					created prior to this date, or even if the file was not yet created when the
					identifier was coined. This attribute is required. Once it is assigned it must
					not be changed, even if the OBJID is changed. </p>
				<p> Computing systems which process files conformant to this profile must preserve
					this date through any transformations, submissions, disseminations, archiving,
					or other operations on the file. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<head>LASTMODDATE</head>
				<p> This date must reflect the date on which any changes to the METS document itself
					occur. This attribute is required, even for newly created METS documents, in
					which case the CREATEDATE and the LASTMODDATE should match. Subsequently, the
					LASTMODDATE must always be after the CREATEDATE. </p>
			</requirement>
			<requirement>
				<head>altRecordID</head>
				<p>When the primary identifier of the METS document as recorded in the OBJID element
					of the mets root element changes due to the creation of a new ECHODep METS file
					for the package, the previous identifier must be recorded as an alternate
					identifier in the altRecordID element. </p>
			</requirement>
		</metsHdr>

		<dmdSec>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not contain descriptive metadata
					elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</dmdSec>

		<amdSec>
			<requirement>
				<head>General Requirements for Administrative Metadata</head>
				<p>This profile requires a single amdSec element for the entire METS document. The
					only allowable sub-element beneath the amdSec is techMD. The arrangement of
					sub-elements is not significant and can be at the convenience of the original
					creator of the file so long as the result conforms to the METS XML schema. The
					reason being that this profile requires all ADMID attributes (of type IDREFS) to
					point directly to techMD elements via those elements' ID attributes. An ADMID
					attribute must not point to the enclosing amdSec, but directly to the relevant
					sub-element. </p>
			</requirement>

			<requirement>
				<head>General Requirements for the Use of PREMIS</head>
				<p> PREMIS object elements are used inside techMD elements. However, the PREMIS
					container element premis is never used. Furthermore, only a single PREMIS object
					element may ever be embedded within a single techMD element. Linkages between
					METS div sections and PREMIS object are made via the METS ID attribute of the
					techMD element containing the PREMIS entity and ADMID attribute of the div. </p>
			</requirement>

			<requirement>
				<head> Technical Metadata for subordinate ECHODep METS files.</head>
				<p> Each subordinate ECHODep METS referenced by a Master METS document must have a
					corresponding techMD section, the content of which must be a PREMIS object
					element embedded in the techMD via the mdWrap element. The PREMIS object element
					must conform to the XML Schema of PREMIS. </p>
				<p> The PREMIS objectCategory element must have a value of 'FILE'. </p>
				<p>The objectCharacteristics element must have at least one fixity sub-element which
					has a messageDigestAlgorithm of 'SHA-1'. The objectCharacteristics element must
					also have a size sub-element; the value of which must be a positive integer
					number representing the size in bytes of the referent file. </p>
				<p> The objectCharacteristics element must have a format sub-element, which has a
					formatDesignation child element, which in turn has a formatName child element.
					The value of the formatName element must be the MIME-type value of the referent
					file.</p>
			</requirement>
		</amdSec>

		<fileSec>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not contain fileSec elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</fileSec>

		<structMap>
			<requirement>
				<head>Primary Structural Map</head>
				<p>This profile requires exactly one structural map, which contains exactly one
					sub-element div. This main div element will contain at least one, but
					potentially several second-level div elements beneath it. Each of these
					second-level div elements must in turn contain exactly one mptr element, which
					references a subordinate ECHODep METS document for the preservation package. </p>

				<head>Second-level div Elements</head>
				<p>Each second-level div element must contain an ADMID and an ORDER attribute. As
					mentioned above in the section on Administrative Metadata, each div must be
					linked to a PREMIS object via the METS ID attribute of the techMD element
					containing the PREMIS entity and ADMID attribute of the div.</p>
				<p>The ORDER attribute is used to record the chronological order in which each
					second-level div was added to the structMap (i.e., the order in which each
					subordinate ECHODep METS file was created). </p>

				<head>METS Pointer Elements (mptrs)</head>
				<p>As described above, each ECHODep METS document for the preservation package is
					referenced from the Master METS document via an mptr element. Each mptr element
					must contain a LOCTYPE attribute with a value of 'URL'. The relative location of
					the ECHODep METS file pointed to must be stored in the element's xlink:href
					attribute. </p>

				<p>For example, when a preservation package is first created the Master METS
					document will reference exactly one subordinate ECHODep METS file for the
					package. The Master METS structMap will contain a top-level div and just one
					second-level div. This second-level div will contain an ADMID that corresponds
					to the METS ID of a techMD section in the amdSec. It will also contain a ORDER
					attribute of '1', since it is the one and only second-level div element so far.
					Finally, it will contain exactly one mptr element that records the location of
					the referent ECHODep METS file. </p>
				<p>When an event triggers the creation of a new ECHODep METS file for the package, a
					new second-level div element containing an mptr will be created as well. This
					div will contain an ADMID that corresponds to the METS ID of a techMD section in
					the amdSec for the newly-created ECHODep METS file, and will have an ORDER
					attribute of '2'. </p>
			</requirement>
		</structMap>

		<structLink>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not contain structLink elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</structLink>

		<behaviorSec>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not contain behaviorSec elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</behaviorSec>
	</structural_requirements>

	<technical_requirements>
		<content_files>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not reference external content files via
					FLocat elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</content_files>

		<behavior_files>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not reference executable behaviors via the
					mechanism element.</p>
			</requirement>
		</behavior_files>

		<metadata_files>
			<requirement>
				<p>Conforming Master METS documents may not reference external metadata files via
					mdRef elements.</p>
			</requirement>
		</metadata_files>

	</technical_requirements>

	<tool>
		<name>Inherited Tools</name>
		<description>
			<p>METS documents which conform to this profile should be compatible with all of the
				tools which are also compatible with the "ECHODep Generic METS Profile for
				Preservation and Digital Repository Interoperability" parent profile.</p>
		</description>
	</tool>

	<Appendix NUMBER="1"
		LABEL="Small Example of a Master METS File Associated with Two EchoDEP METS Files">
		<mets xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
			xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/"
			xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
			xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd 
			http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/xlink.xsd 
			http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/v1 http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/v1/PREMIS-v1-1.xsd"
			PROFILE="http://www.loc.gov/mets/profiles/00000???.xml" LABEL="Sunday Verification"
			OBJID="hdl:123456789/1">
			<metsHdr LASTMODDATE="2008-09-02T19:12:18.458-05:00"
				CREATEDATE="2008-09-02T15:47:00.411-05:00">
				<altRecordID>hdl:123456789/1</altRecordID>
			</metsHdr>
			<amdSec>
				<techMD ID="ID1" CREATED="2008-09-02T20:47:10.380Z">
					<mdWrap MDTYPE="PREMIS" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
						<xmlData>
							<object type="file" version="1.1"
								xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/v1">
								<objectIdentifier>
									<objectIdentifierType>URL</objectIdentifierType>
									<objectIdentifierValue>echodepmets_0.xml</objectIdentifierValue>
								</objectIdentifier>
								<objectCategory>FILE</objectCategory>
								<objectCharacteristics>
									<compositionLevel>0</compositionLevel>
									<fixity>
										<messageDigestAlgorithm>SHA-1</messageDigestAlgorithm>
										<messageDigest>fe679dd91c68b04d33afb6dff5e2fedc9efc046c</messageDigest>
									</fixity>
									<fixity>
										<messageDigestAlgorithm>MD5</messageDigestAlgorithm>
										<messageDigest>07373efeaa013e2fb60ce4050cb4f887</messageDigest>
									</fixity>
									<size>4536</size>
									<format>
										<formatDesignation>
											<formatName>text/xml</formatName>
										</formatDesignation>
									</format>
								</objectCharacteristics>
							</object>
						</xmlData>
					</mdWrap>
				</techMD>
				<techMD ID="ID2" CREATED="2008-09-03T00:12:18.427Z">
					<mdWrap MDTYPE="PREMIS" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
						<xmlData>
							<object type="file" version="1.1"
								xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/v1">
								<objectIdentifier>
									<objectIdentifierType>URL</objectIdentifierType>
									<objectIdentifierValue>echodepmets_1.xml</objectIdentifierValue>
								</objectIdentifier>
								<objectCategory>FILE</objectCategory>
								<objectCharacteristics>
									<compositionLevel>0</compositionLevel>
									<fixity>
										<messageDigestAlgorithm>SHA-1</messageDigestAlgorithm>
										<messageDigest>79fdc481156f3f1434de562ef7b160b5269110de</messageDigest>
									</fixity>
									<fixity>
										<messageDigestAlgorithm>MD5</messageDigestAlgorithm>
										<messageDigest>431c73696acebe1e605183e2a32b1597</messageDigest>
									</fixity>
									<size>25252</size>
									<format>
										<formatDesignation>
											<formatName>text/xml</formatName>
										</formatDesignation>
									</format>
								</objectCharacteristics>
							</object>
						</xmlData>
					</mdWrap>
				</techMD>
			</amdSec>
			<structMap TYPE="PRIMARY_STRUCTMAP">
				<div>
					<div ADMID="ID1" ORDER="1">
						<mptr LOCTYPE="URL" xlin:href="echodepmets_0.xml"
							xmlns:xlin="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
					</div>
					<div ADMID="ID2" ORDER="2">
						<mptr LOCTYPE="URL" xlin:href="echodepmets_1.xml"
							xmlns:xlin="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
					</div>
				</div>
			</structMap>
		</mets>

	</Appendix>
</METS_Profile>
